John, thank you very much for joining us
today. Abra Silver has released a lot of
significant news here in the last couple
of weeks, so I thought it would be a
good time to sit down with you and get a
quick update. Some of that news included
a definitive feasibility study and also
a $50 million equity raise. And before
we discuss these updates in detail, why
don't we just start with a brief
overview of Abra Silver for those
viewers who might not be familiar with
the company. Where is it located and
where are you hoping to mine?
>> Great. Yeah, no, thanks very much, Jim,
for for having me back on. As you
mentioned, look, a lot has happened
since we last spoke. Of course, Abra
Silver, our key asset, Diablillos, this
is one of the largest, fully permitted,
uh, primary silver projects in the
world. This is a large-scale resource.
We have 250 million oz of silver, 2.5
million oz of gold. So, on a silver
equivalent basis, that's almost 500
million oz,
uh, on a silver equivalent basis at
current commodity prices. So, this is,
uh, a very, very large project. Uh, um,
this is located in the Salta and
Catamarca provinces of Argentina,
located close to surface, open pittable
in oxides with very straightforward
metallurgy.
Um, so, this is, uh, you know, a
large-scale project, but as you
mentioned, I think where Abra Silver has
really undergone a transformational
shift over the last 6 months, uh, or so,
since since we last spoke. You know, our
our exploration team over the last
several years has done a phenomenal job
for us just consistently growing,
drilling the resource, uh, growing the
resource every single year.
Um, but now where we're at,
uh, we now, again, have turned this
discovery into a into a real project
that's now ready to be constructed. So,
recently we announced our definitive
feasibility study.
We received our environmental approvals
in both provinces, in Salta and
Catamarca.
Uh, and then we also received Riggi
approval, which we can discuss as well
in Argentina. That's obviously
absolutely critical.
Uh so now we've you know and we've grown
the resource as well. And as you
mentioned we closed the $50 million
financing recently which went extremely
well. So we've really made the
transition. We're no longer an explorer.
We're now a developer.
You know the project's large scale, you
know, very very robust. We can talk
about the economics of the DFS.
Um and yeah Diablillos is really in a in
a very rare category globally I'd say.
Uh so it's one of the the largest
primary silver projects now advancing
towards a final construction decision.
Uh and our job here is on on execution.
>> So let's discuss the definitive
feasibility study. Now the whole purpose
of this study is to prove up the
economics. What are the net present
value and what is the internal rate of
return?
>> Yeah I know. So the the study has very
very robust economics and importantly
the study was done at a very
conservative commodity prices. So we
used $50 for silver long term, $3,650
for gold. So of course well below where
we're sitting today.
Um and based on those conservative
assumptions the headline NPV was $4.2
billion Canadian
at a 5% discount rate
over 40% after tax rate of return. Uh
this is a large again large project 25
year mine life running at 9,000 tons per
day
um throughput rate. And importantly the
payback is extremely short. So payback
is under two years. Uh so I think it was
1.7 years at the base case.
Uh we'll be producing over 20 million
ounces silver equivalent over the first
five years. And again this is 100%
precious metals focused. So over the
life of mine it's about 65% of the
revenue silver
and about 1/3 would would be gold.
Um very very low all-in sustaining cash
costs around $20 an ounce, making one of
one of the lowest uh cost primary silver
projects out there globally.
Uh and we have a $720 million as our
initial CapEx
uh with first production targeted before
the end of 2029. So, this is, you know,
important to note as well, I'd say that
this is really phase one of this project
by design. I mean, uh there's still
significant expansion opportunities
here. We can add plant capacity, we can
expand through uh also adding a heap
leach circuit as well. Um, and so, you
know, this DFS really solidifies phase
one.
Uh obviously, our goal now is to get
that up and running, and then we're also
going to be looking at at some of those
expansion scenarios here in a lot of
detail uh over the next six six months.
>> And John, you mentioned that the silver
equivalent production will be 20 million
ounces. Um, what's the actual breakdown
between silver and gold?
>> Yeah, so in the peak years, I think year
two and three are the peak production
years, we're actually going to be
producing 19 million ounces of just
silver. Uh and then over on a silver
equivalent basis, another 6 million
ounces or so would come from the gold
component. So, combined, that's 25
million ounces. But yeah, 19 million of
that comes from silver. Uh and then I
think in in the year three, uh it would
be 17 million ounces of just silver. And
so, we actually have a chart in our um
in our slide deck, our corporate
presentation, that shows you in year
three, the Yellowhead would actually be
the largest primary silver mine
globally, uh where, you know, silver
counts for more than 50% of revenue. So,
right now, I think Saint Cristobal has
that in in Bolivia. It's about 17
million ounces. And yeah, again, we'd be
19 million ounces in year three of just
silver with gold as a byproduct on top
of that. So, this is really
the largest will be the largest primary
silver mine globally and ranks
comfortably in the top 10, even in the
top five, I'd say,
over the the life of mine.
>> And now that this study has been
released, what are the next steps? And I
guess the a big decision is going to
have to be the construction decision.
>> Exactly. Yeah, no, so it it's not just a
steady again. I mean, the permits, we
have those. So, those came as well. So,
we received the Salta approval, I think
it was back in April,
Catamarca approval as well back in June.
So, at the provincial level, we're fully
permitted. At the federal level, we also
received a RIGGI approval. That's
critical for us. So, that's the new at
the federal level, there's this
large-scale
investment
sort of incentive, which provides stable
sort of fiscal framework for 30-year
period.
And so, with this, I mean, we're the
only developer in Argentina that has
RIGGI approval in place. The other
companies that have RIGGI approval
already are all the majors. So,
Newmont's, Barrick's, Rio Tinto's,
Glencore's, etc., BHP.
And then, Abra Silver also has RIGGI.
So, we really stand out
and I think RIGGI has has been a
transformational for us. Again, this
stabilizes your taxes, it eliminates
export duties, import duties,
eliminates all the foreign exchange
restrictions. And so, with RIGGI, I'd
say Argentina has again truly become
genuinely sort of an investable mining
jurisdiction again.
And again, this is one of the the
projects that that benefits the most
from that regime.
So, we received Yeah, we completed our
feasibility, we got our permits, we got
RIGGI. And so, now really, the execution
here is building the team internally and
raising the financing needed to move
this into construction. And I think we
we've done a great job advancing both of
those as well, which which we can touch
upon.
>> And when are you going to make a final
construction decision?
>> April. So April of 2027.
So between now and then, we're
finalizing sort of detailed engineering.
Again, hiring some some key pieces on
the the technical side. So recently, we
promoted Jeremy Wayland,
who led the the technical work for us on
the DFS.
He's now moved up to the COO role. He's
running sort of the development
construction readiness here.
We're looking to make a few key hires
now in Argentina as well.
And then on the the corporate side,
Marie Engster has stepped in as our exec
chair. So of course, Marie is very well
known in the industry. She was CFO of
Lundin Mining for about a decade or so.
Was also CEO of Lundin Mining. So she's
running, you know, a multi-billion
dollar sort of base metal producer.
And so that's exactly the experience
that that we want obviously on our board
as we're getting ready to to make that
final build decision next year.
>> And if everything goes according to
plan, when are you hoping to go into
production?
>> Before the end of 2029.
So it's about 2 and 1/2 year
construction timeline here.
And so yeah, right now, it'll be Q4 2029
when we hit commercial production.
>> Okay, so that's a great overview. Let's
talk about the recent financing. You
raised $50 million at a price of 1470
Canadian per share, and the stock's
significantly higher right now. So I can
only assume the deal went well, but
maybe you can just talk on the deal. Who
were the participants? Were they
Canadians, Americans, Europeans, retail,
institutional?
>> Yeah, I know. The the deal was well over
subscribed, so the demand was well north
of 50 million Canadian, but we capped it
at that level.
Yeah, we had support from from our
largest sort of institutional investors.
So Helicon, of course, is is our our top
shareholder. They own over 10% of the
company, a very successful fund based
out of London. They participated.
Several of our other institutional
investors participated as well.
And then, of course, Kinross also
exercised their participation right.
So Kinross maintained 4% prior to the
equity financing and then elected to to
finance sort of pro rata to maintain
their their 4% threshold. So this was a
great, you know, it was minimal
dilution, less than 10%. Oh, sorry, less
than 2%
of the shares outstanding here. So this
was a relatively small financing, went
extremely well. Now we're fully cashed
up
and we're obviously now advancing sort
of discussions on the larger sort of
financing package required to take this
into construction. Again, as I
mentioned, we have a $720 million US
initial CapEx figure from the the
recently completed feasibility study.
That's going to require balanced sort of
approach, of course.
There could be some some term debt.
Could potentially be a silver gold
stream here
and then potentially for for some
additional equity.
So we're we're really in active sort of
conversation across all three of those.
I think this project's clearly very,
very financeable. Right now we're, you
know, I think in a in a great position.
Lots and lots of options available to
us. So we'll carefully examine all of
those and by the end of this year
looking to to announce sort of the the,
you know, financing package sort of
details.
>> So the $50 million was just a short-term
financing or bridge financing to get you
through to the project financing
decision.
>> Yes. Yeah, it puts us in a very strong
negotiating position as well. Uh so, we
previously had about $20 million in the
bank. Now, we have 70 million. Uh so,
you know, obviously, I think we're we're
in a very strong position. We can start
doing some early works construction
activities. We can now start ordering
some long lead time items as well. So,
as we're having those discussions, we're
moving the project forward. But, it it's
pretty limited spending, I'd say, over
the next few months. So, this was really
just to to reinforce the the strength of
the balance sheet, make sure we we don't
run that too low in terms of our cash
position. So, again, this was a, you
know, executed that that financing very
very well. You know, the the
shareholders are are very happy, the
strategic shareholders.
Uh and now, we're very comfortably in in
a great position here to secure the the
larger financing package later this
year.
>> And John, do you Are you still drilling
at site? And if so, how many rigs do you
have on the
>> [laughter]
>> Very important. I mean, so that with
everything going on, I think, you know,
it's very important to to highlight
exploration has not gone away here. This
is still There's still lots of upside. I
think this is another thing that makes
Diablo Los very very unique. Typically,
when you're at the DFS stage, you know,
the exploration's behind you. You're
kind of infill drilling or or doing
condemnation drilling. For us, our phase
six program is still focused on step-out
drill results and continues to have some
some great intercepts. I think it was in
July we announced the one of, you know,
a phenomenal hole there, over 100 m,
over 220 g of silver,
uh and 0.7 g of gold. Uh that's at at
Aculpato West. Uh so, we're still
finding high-grade material outside of
the the current mine plan.
And so we'll be updating the resource
again next year
and then all of this exploration upside
will help us as we're looking at these
study
expansions as well. As I mentioned, we
could expand the throughput capacity
and a number of other items that we're
looking at. So, you know, the current
resource makes
phase one extremely robust.
But we're looking well beyond phase one
already.
So exploration continues to play a
pivotal role for us and there's still a
lot of exploration upside especially in
that that Oculto East area that hasn't
been very well defined as of yet. So
we're we're not stopping the exploration
at all. I think there's a clear path
ahead. If anything, we could become a
bit more aggressive and and add a few
more rigs
and start drilling that that faster. So
I expect a steady stream of news flow
here
well until year-end and and into next
year as well from the current
exploration program.
>> Well, this has been a great update,
John, and I want to thank you very much
for spending time with us today. And as
we wrap up, maybe you can just summarize
what we can expect in terms of news flow
from Abra Silver in the coming months.
>> Yeah, I know. So thanks thanks again,
Jimmy, for for having me back on. I
think yeah, in terms of a summary, I
think we we covered all all the key
details there. I think the the message
is clear. Abra Silver, we're no longer
just an exploration story anymore. We
have a very large-scale permitted,
highly economic silver gold development
project, very robust economics
in a jurisdiction that's improved
dramatically
and we still have real expansion upside
ahead of us. So in terms of news flow,
lots going on. So you'll see us continue
to build out the technical team later on
this year. Of course, looking to have a
fully financed
sort of project
and of course exploration will continue
to provide lots and lots of highlights
here, I would imagine. So, a lot going
on at the moment, and then next year is
when the construction activities begin,
and we're really then sort of looking to
to re-rate into that developer category
rather than again still being treated as
as an exploration company.
>> John, once again, thank you.
>> My pleasure.